If you think your family's different, wait 'til
you meet the family of the future.
Meet the Robinsons is a animation, comedy, family
film directed by Stephen J. Anderson.
Lewis, a brilliant young inventor, is keen on creating a time machine
to find his mother, who abandoned him in an orphanage.
Things take a turn when he meets Wilbur Robinson and his family.
Lewis (voice), played by Daniel Hansen.
Lewis (voice), played by Jordan Fry.
Wilbur (voice), played by Wesley Singerman.
Michael 'Goob' Yagoobian (voice), played by Matthew Josten.
Bowler Hat Guy / Grandpa Bud / Tallulah (voice), played by Stephen J. Anderson.
Cornelius Robinson (voice), played by Tom Selleck.
Meet the Robinsons is a 2007 American animated science fiction comedy film produced by Walt Disney
Animation Studios, based on the 1990 children's book A Day with Wilbur Robinson by William Joyce.
The film was directed by Stephen Anderson, and written by Anderson, Don Hall, Nathan Greno, Joe Mateo, Jon Bernstein, Michelle Spitz, and Aurian Redson, and stars the voices of Daniel
Hansen, Jordan Fry, Wesley Singerman, Angela Bassett, Tom Selleck, Harland Williams, Laurie Metcalf, Nicole Sullivan, Adam West, Ethan Sandler, Tom Kenny, and Anderson.
It follows an orphaned 12-year-old inventor,
Lewis, who is desperate to be adopted.
He meets Wilbur Robinson, a young time-traveler who takes him
to the year 2037 to visit his eccentric family.
They must prevent a mysterious bowler-hatted man from
changing Lewis's fate, and, by proxy, the future.
Development began in 2002, with production starting in 2004 under the working title A
Day with Wilbur Robinson, with a release initially slated for 2006.
Anderson developed a personal connection to the main character, Lewis,
as he himself grew up an orphan and was later adopted.
Disney originally planned to adopt Joyce's style, but it was decided to slightly rework
the style due to his involvement stylistically in Blue Sky Studios' Robots.
The animation crew had the challenge to animate CG humans,
being inspired by Pixar's The Incredibles.
Inspiration for the film came from Disney animated classics, such as Alice in
Wonderland, Cinderella, and Peter Pan, as well as Warner Bros.
Cartoons, to capture a 1950s aesthetic.
Disney's acquisition of Pixar in early 2006 led to nearly 60% of the film,
including the villain and the ending, being scrapped and reworked.
Danny Elfman composed the film's score, while artists such as Rufus Wainwright, Rob Thomas, The
All-American Rejects, and They Might Be Giants contributed to its soundtrack.
Meet the Robinsons premiered at the El Capitan Theatre in Los Angeles on March
25, 2007, and was released in the United States on March 30, 2007.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics but was a box office
disappointment, grossing $170.5 million against a budget of $150 million.
The film explores themes of future, friendship, flying car,
saving the world, based on novel or book.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.